# **Brooke Walters, Data Scientist**

Intellectually curious, creative, and systematic **analytics professional with 8+ years' experience** in market research and insights analysis. Effective at building influential relationships and delivering impactful insights to executives. Currently pursuing a M.S. in **Data Science & Analytics**.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Associate Data Scientist, PillarFour Media

Grand Rapids, MI | October 2023 - June 2024

- Deployed end-to-end machine learning models, from feature engineering, hyperparameter tuning, and model optimization, utilizing gradient boosting and neural networks to anticipate future market trends.
- Ensured data integrity and consistency within AWS Redshift by updating tables and utilizing SQL subqueries as integral components of the data science pipeline.
- Engineered interactive R Shiny and Flexdashboard interfaces, enhancing data accessibility and visualization for stakeholders.
- Collaborated with UX research and digital marketing teams on cross-functional
  modeling projects, analyzing web traffic to identify website optimization opportunities
  and enhance user experience. Delivered comprehensive code reviews (QA) and
  technical feedback, leading to measurable improvements in campaign performance
  validated through statistically significant A/B testing.

#### Senior Insights Analyst, Corewell Health

Grand Rapids, MI | May 2022 - October 2023

- Collected, transformed, and quantified statistically significant market research results, cutting the feedback loop from months to minutes. Developed real-time ticketing solution for patient concerns, streamlining operations and response times.
- Deployed natural language processing (NLP) tools for in-depth consumer sentiment
  analysis and thematic categorization. Embedded results into dynamic dashboards
  accessed daily by operations, resulting in the validation of special projects and
  exceeding consumer experience benchmark goals.
- Utilized R programming language and Tableau to aggregate and analyze population health data and market trends, translating findings into actionable insights for competitive intelligence. Analysis informed strategic decisions, enabling teams to proactively identify and capitalize on growth opportunities.

# Market Research & Insights Analyst, Spectrum Reach

Grand Rapids, MI | January 2016 - May 2022

- Analyzed consumer behavior and communicated key findings through data visualizations, presentations, and written summaries, directly contributed to an increase of \$3.4 million in ad revenue.
- Curated and distributed daily newsletters, updating local sales teams across the U.S. on emerging multiplatform advertising trends bolstering Spectrum Reach's reputation as a knowledgeable leader in audience-based multiscreen advertising solutions.

#### **ACADEMIC DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS**

Data Mining: Crime in Colorado | April 2023

Spatial and temporal analysis of the relationship between dispensary density and crime
rates using linear regression modeling in R. Joined open-source datasets from the
Colorado Department of Revenue and the FBI Uniform Crime Reporting Program.

Statisical Modeling and Regression: Seasonal Inventory Prediction | August 2023

 Developed and evaluated a Poisson regression model to forecast weekly inventory demand, utilizing time series analysis and feature engineering techniques in R.

## CONTACT



Brooke.Melissa.Walters@gmail.com



616-780-9024



linkedin.com/in/bmwlters/



brookemwalters.github.io/Collection/

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Grand Valley State University**

Data Science and Analytics, M.S (current) GPA 3.965

#### **Grand Valley State University**

Advertising and Public Relations, B.S. Minor, Business

## **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** R, SQL Python

**Predictive Modeling**: TidyModels, Linear and Logistic Regression

**Project Management:** Collaborative Problem Solving, Salesforce, GitHub, Notion

**Business Acumen:** Primary Market Research, Presentations, Reporting, Stakeholder Engagement

**Data Manipulation and Analysis:** Data Cleaning, Data Mining, Data Aggregation

**Data Visualization:** Tableau, Microsoft Office Suite, Neustar, rShiny